Finding aid to Alumnae Oral History Project collection CA.MS.00301
Smith College Archives
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2012), Accession 2012-A-0026
  - Monica Ricci Sargentini (AMS 1987) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 24; 1 oral histories
    In this oral history, Monica Ricci Sargentini contrasts her education experience in Italy with Smith, specifically in regard to classes and social expectations. She talks about her academic interest in language and American literature, interests that drew her to the AMS Diploma Program. She ends her interview with a discussion about the value of women's colleges in general and the American approach to life.
    - Video interview with Monica Ricci Sargentini
    - Transcript of interview with Monica Ricci Sargentini (Box 7)
  - Group interview (Class of 1957) with Gail Richards Blunt, Ann Loomis Jesse, Joan Millspaugh, Judy Oksner, and Elizabeth Mayor, interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories
    In this oral history, Gail Richards Blunt, Ann Loomis Jesse, Elizabeth Mayor, Joan Millspaugh, and Judy Oksner describe what it was like to be at Smith during the 1950s, their relationships with their housemothers, knitting during classes, the dating scene, expectations for them when they graduated in terms of marriage and work, and where their lives have taken them since leaving Smith.
    - Video interview of Class of 1957 group
    - Transcript of interview with Class of 1957 group (Box 7)
  - Group interview (Class of 1982) with Caroline Ely, Winn Gilmore, and Sue Marcoux, interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories
    This interview is available for research only to members of the Smith community.
    In this oral history Caroline Ely, Winn Gilmore, and Susan Marcoux discuss their decisions to come to Smith, the differences between the Smith and Northampton lesbian scenes, Hover and Tenney Houses as epicenters of lesbian culture at Smith, their experiences in Lesbian Alliance, homophobia and racial tension on campus, and the tensions in the lesbian communities at Smith.
    - Video interview with Class of 1982
    - Transcript of group interview with Class of 1982 (Box 7)
  - Original videotapes and preservation master DVDs, 2012; 1 boxes (miniDV tapes) (Box 8)
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2013), Accession 2012-A-0026
  - Jennifer Barone (Class of 2008) interviewed by Rachel Klinger, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research only to members of the Smith community. No online access.
    In this oral history, Jennifer Barone recalls political and social justice issues around race, sexual orientation and class on campus during her time at Smith and the student and administration response to those issues. She reflects on finding her voice at Smith and speaks about how she feels returning to Smith for reunion helps graduates stay connected to the sense of empowerment they experienced here.
    - Video interview with Jennifer Barone
    - Transcript of interview with Jennifer Barone (Box 9)
  - Christine Boutin (Class of 1988) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, recorded on the occasion of her 25th reunion, Christine Boutin speaks about the importance of lifelong friendships which began at Smith and remembers Smith traditions, including Thursday night candlelight suppers and Friday teas. She recalls social justice activism on campus, including participation in the College Hall divestiture sit-in as well as challenges like experiencing class differences in the student body.
    - Video interview with Christine Boutin
    - Transcript of interview with Christine Boutin (Box 9)
  - Lisa Bischoff Brassord (Class of 1983) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Lia Brassord, who has attended nearly every reunion since graduation, discusses the importance of that experience in her life. She reflects on the intergenerational bonds she has witnessed at Smith and the importance of the underlying qualities that cross those and other boundaries among Smithies.
    - Video interview with Lisa Brassord
    - Transcript of interview with Lisa Brassord (Box 9)
  - Ravelle Brickman (Class of 1958) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Ravelle Brickman observes the changes she has seen on the Smith campus over the years, including the growing diversity of the student body. She reflects on her political activism at Smith and other highlights of her college years, including as a columnist for The Sophian and her role in founding of the Grecourt Review that published writers including Sylvia Plath.
    - Video interview with Ravelle Brickman
    - Transcript of interview with Ravelle Brickman (Box 9)
  - Ruth R. Budd (Class of 1958) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Ruth Budd recalls seeing Smith for the first time when she arrived alone as a first-year from Colorado. She speaks of the important role of women's colleges and remembers her junior year abroad in Geneva in 1956, during the Hungarian Revolution, and the life-long friendship that began during that experience.
    - Video interview with Ruth R. Budd
    - Transcript of interview with Ruth R. Budd (Box 9)
  - Kara Callahan (Class of 1988) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Kara Callahan discusses the deep connection she feels with Smith and the importance of attending a women's college. She expresses a delight in traditions like Convocation and Rally Day as formative in giving students a sense of what it means to be a "Smith woman."
    - Video interview with Kara Callahan
    - Transcript of interview with Kara Callahan (Box 9)
  - Elizabeth B. Campen (Class of 1958) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Elizabeth Campen reflects on the house culture at Smith which, in the 1950s, included house mothers. She recalls fondly traditions which no longer exist on campus, including Wednesday chapel. Campen talks about the importance of the legacy of a Smith education, the confidence that Smithies can do anything.
    - Video interview with Elizabeth B. Campen
    - Transcript of interview with Elizabeth B. Campen (Box 9)
  - Alexandra Dellerson (Class of 2008) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research only to members of the Smith Community.
    In this oral history, Alexandra Dellerson speaks about the importance of Smith's challenging academic environment as well as the open discussions of gender and sexuality. She recalls political and social issues on campus, including race and the presence of transgender students on campus and how the energy generated by that political climate contributed to her college experience.
    - Video interview with Alexandra Dellerson
    - Transcript of interview with Alexandra Dellerson (Box 9)
  - Carol Dwyer (Class of 1958) interviewed by Ellice Amanna, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Carol Dwyer reflects on the changes she has seen take place at Smith, the importance of the friendships she made in her house, and the opportunities for travel and exploration that accompanied her Junior Year abroad.
    - Video interview with Carol Dwyer
    - Transcript of interview with Carol Dwyer (Box 9)
  - Barbara Dybwad (Class of 1998) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Barbara Dybwad speaks about the powerful effect of the Smith network in her life. She discusses the Smithenpoofs and the central role that group played in her college experience. She recalls classes that enriched her life as well as the unique experience and the camaraderie that developed during finals exams and the importance for her of the seriousness with which students approach academics at Smith.
    - Video interview with Barbara Dybwad
    - Transcript of interview with Barbara Dybwad (Box 9)
  - Susan Elliott (Class of 1958) interviewed by Ellice Amanna, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Susan Elliot, returning on the occasion of her 55th reunion, reflects on the importance of friendships formed through Smith's house culture and remembers house activities including playing bridge after supper with housemates. She recalls a meeting with a Smith advisor that lead to her to a new recruitment program that IBM had launched for women and how that became the foundation for her future business success.
    - Video interview with Susan Elliott
    - Transcript of interview with Susan Elliott (Box 9)
  - Martha Clough Engeman and Nancy Hutchens Reif (Class of 1983) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, done with classmate Nancy Hutchens Reif on the occasion of their 30th reunion, the women discuss how their meeting as freshmen lead to a lifetime relationship as best friends. They recall traveling to Paris together, including visiting the Smith office. They also reflect on the importance of Smith traditions, including Friday tea and Thursday night dinners. They recall political controversy on campus, such as an outcry against Jeane Kirkpatrick delivering the commencement address, as well as being on campus during the assassinations of Anwar Sadat and the murder of John Lennon.
    - Video interview with Martha Clough Engeman and Nancy Hutchens Reif
    - Transcript of interview with Martha Clough Engeman and Nancy Hutchens Reif (Box 9)
  - Rosalie Horne Franks (Class of 1958) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Rosalie Horne Franks talks about why she has attended every Smith reunion since graduation in 1958. She discusses her experience of entering Smith at 16 as well as her observations of how Smith has changed, including the growing diversity of the student body and the global nature of the curriculum and the student population.
    - Video interview with Rosalie Horne Franks
    - Transcript of interview with Rosalie Horne Franks (Box 9)
  - Fievel Gordon (Class of 2004) and Erica Hieggelke (Class of 2003) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Feivel Gordon and Erica Hieggelke, who met as first-years, reflect with candor and humor on their evolution as a couple. Feivel discusses his own process of self-discovery while at Smith and they speak candidly about the issue of transsexual students attending all-women's schools. They also recall being together on 9/11 and the aftermath of that trauma on campus.
    - Video interview with Feivel Gordon and Erica Hieggelke
    - Transcript of interview with Feivel Gordon and Erica Hieggelke (Box 9)
  - Margaret Miller Greer (Class of 1978) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Margaret Miller Greer speaks about the critical role that the self-confidence she acquired during her Smith years played in helping her meet future challenges. She recalls favorite Smith traditions, including tea and vespers, the importance of lifelong friendships she formed at Smith and wise words from Jill Kerr Conway.
    - Video interview with Margaret Miller Greer
    - Transcript of interview with Margaret Miller Greer (Box 9)
  - Theanne Griffith (Class of 2008) interviewed by Rachel Klinger, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Theanne Griffith speaks of choosing to attend Smith because of its neuroscience program, her involvement with the Black Students Alliance and the Smith Democrats, as well as the Underrepresented Science Students group on campus. She speaks of the overall importance of maintaining a diverse student population and how her experiences with issues of diversity at Smith prepared her for her future.
    - Video interview with Theanne Griffith
    - Transcript of interview with Theanne Griffith (Box 9)
  - Jennifer Lynn Harmon (Class of 2003) interviewed by Rachel Klinger, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Jennifer Harmon reflects on her experience as a woman of color at Smith, the benefits of the Bridge program, political issues on campus around race and sexual orientation during her years on campus, and the importance of her house community in her Smith experience.
    - Video interview with Jennifer Lynn Harmon
    - Transcript of interview with Jennifer Lynn Harmon (Box 9)
  - Ali Harris (Class of 2008) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Ali Harris speaks about treasured Smith traditions, including Friday tea, which provided a space for her and her housemates to detach from the pressure of academic life, pause and reflect, and enjoy each other socially. She speaks of the a commitment to community which she learned at Smith. She also recalls the mentors she met at Smith and the important role that mentorship played in her Smith life and beyond.
    - Video interview with Ali Harris
    - Transcript of interview with Ali Harris (Box 9)
  - Allison Hector (Class of 2003) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Allison Hector discusses the political environment during her college years, including the Iraq War and being on campus during the attack on the World Trade Center on 9/11 which occurred only weeks before she embarked on her junior year abroad. She recalls the importance of being with her Smith family during that difficult period and some memorable events, including Madeline Albright delivering her class's commencement address.
    - Video interview with Allison Hector
    - Transcript of interview with Allison Hector (Box 9)
  - Celeste Hemingson (Class of 1963) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Celeste Hemingson recalls the backdrop of political activism that marked her time at Smith, including student sit-ins to integrate the lunch counter at the Northampton Woolworths. She observes how her Smith experience gave her a love of learning and the self-confidence to pursue her passions, including becoming a priest.
    - Video interview with Celeste Hemingson
    - Transcript of interview with Celeste Hemingson (Box 9)
  - Julia Hudson (Class of 2008) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Julia Hudson talks about her views on Smith traditions, particularly Convocation, and the importance of the school's house culture, especially in formation of strong, lasting friendships. She discusses the way political thinking was developed in conversation with other Smithies and how issues of race, religion and sex were all part of the conversation.
    - Video interview with Julia Hudson
    - Transcript of interview with Julia Hudson (Box 9)
  - Toni Trobe Kestenbaum (Class of 1963) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Toni Kestenbaum, who has attended every reunion since graduation, speaks of the affirming importance of this gathering. She also reflects on the changes she has witnessed over the years, including the diversity of the student body and an openness to sexual identity differences. She attributes her successful career in finance and business to the foundation she received at Smith.
    - Video interview with Toni Kestenbaum
    - Transcript of interview with Toni Kestenbaum (Box 9)
  - Alix Kolar (Class of 1998) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Alix Kolar speaks about the unique environment on the Smith campus and the foundation in critical thinking and breadth of interests that her Smith education provided. She recalls her favorite Smith traditions, including Friday teas, which remain important.
    - Video interview with Alix Kolar
    - Transcript of interview with Alix Kolar (Box 9)
  - Cindy Kohlbry (Class of 1978) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Cindy Kohlbry recalls her love of Smith's theater department and the professors who made long-lasting impressions on her life. She reflects on some of the extra-curricular activities which shaped her Smith experience, including performing with the Smithenpoofs and the enduring friendships which were formed in that singing group.
    - Video interview with Cindy Kohlbry
    - Transcript of interview of Cindy Kohlbry (Box 9)
  - Susan Korgen (Class of 1983) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Susan Korgen, who is back on campus for her 25th reunion, reflects on her decision to go to Smith and speaks about her experience as a scholarship student and the class and racial differences she observed in the student body. She speaks about the influence going to Smith has had on her career, including a foundation of self-confidence that she attributes to the even playing field she that Smith created.
    - Video interview with Susan Korgen
    - Transcript of interview with Susan Korgen (Box 9)
  - Lisa Lauterbach Laskin (Class of 1988) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research without restriction. No video online.
    In this oral history, Lisa Lauterbach Laskin, whose mother was Smith Class of 1957, reflects on the way Smith has changed since her mother's years. She talks about her favorite tradition, Mountain Day, and the pleasure of spontaneity that it taught her.
    - Video interview with Lisa Lauterbach Laskin
    - Transcript of interview with Lisa Lauterbach Laskin (Box 9)
  - Kate Lehmann (Class of 1978) interviewed by Ellice Amanna, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Kate Lehmann recalls the Women's Movement and lesbian activism as significant pieces of the political backdrop during her Smith years, as well as her experience living in Greer Street rooming house. She speaks of the many ways Smith prepared her for the future by helping her develop analytical thinking and self-confidence.
    - Video interview with Kate Lehmann
    - Transcript of interview with Kate Lehmann (Box 9)
  - Sharon Leyhow (Class of 1973) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research to the Smith community only. No video online.
    In this oral history, Sharon Leyhow recalls the political climate during her years at Smith, including student protests against the Vietnam War and other events and issues. She recalls her involvement with the Black Students Alliance and their activism to bring African-American Studies to Smith, and affect other changes.
    - Video interview with Sharon Leyhow
    - Transcript of interview with Sharon Leyhow (Box 9)
  - Lori Lober (Class of 1983) interviewed by Ellice Amanna, 2013 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research. No online access. No video online.
    In this oral history, Lori Lober speaks of feminism and its role in her Smith experience, including activism around the Women's Resource Center and the founding of Take Back the Night, as well as rape counseling and Lesbian Alliance workshops, and recalls stories of her experience as part of the Jewish Students Alliance. She credits her Smith education with her ability to reason, make a cogent argument and write effectively.
    - Video interview with Lori Lober
    - Transcript of interview with Lori Lober (Box 9)
  - Allison Maranuk (Class of 2008) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research to the Smith community only. No online access.
    In this oral history, Allison Maranuk, speaks of how her activism at Smith prepared her for her career. She recalls the politically-charged climate during her Smith years, four years which began during the Bush-Kerry election, included the recession and the Iraq War, and came to an end with graduation in the year of President Obama's election.
    - Video interview with Allison Maranuk
    - Transcript of interview with Allison Maranuk (Box 10)
  - Leslie D. Mark (Class of 1983) interviewed by Ellice Amanna, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Leslie Mark, who serves on the Smith Board of Directors, discusses her strong connection to the college. She speaks of the continuing importance of the Smith network in her life and the local alumnae chapters she's been a part of.
    - Video interview with Leslie D. Mark
    - Transcript of interview with Leslie D. Mark (Box 10)
  - Leslie G. McKenzie (Class of 1968) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Leslie McKenzie, a philosophy of religion major, recalls the professors and classes that made strong marks on her life and tells stories of unique teaching moments which she has never forgotten. She also recalls the difference that living in a small house made in her college experience.
    - Video interview with Leslie G. McKenzie
    - Transcript of interview with Leslie G. McKenzie (Box 10)
  - Jane M. Moffett (Class of 1954) interviewed by Annie Ames, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Jane Moffett recalls the extraordinary caliber of Smith's Art History Department which became the center of her life during her college years and beyond. She relates stories that shaped her worldview, including a conversation with Ruth Simmons that changed her life.
    - Video interview with Jane Moffett
    - Transcript of interview with Jane Moffett (Box 10)
  - Lisa Perry Morales (AC 1988) interviewed by Rachel Klinger, 2013 May 17; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Lisa Morales speaks of her unique path to Smith and challenges faced by many Ada Comstock Scholars. Morales speaks of attending Smith for three years with as the mother of a young son. She recalls bringing her mother to her first Illumination Night and the importance of that and other experiences for them both.
    - Video interview with Lisa Perry Morales
    - Transcript of interview with Lisa Perry Morales (Box 10)
  - Claire Goldberg Moses (Class of 1963) interviewed by Carolyn Rees, 2013 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Claire Goldberg Moses reflects on the occasion of the 50th class reunion. She speaks of the important role the house culture played in her college experience and on the central role her Junior Year abroad in Paris played in her life. She recalls a progressive political environment at Smith, which included Civil Rights demonstrations in front of the Northampton Woolworth building.
    - Video interview with Claire Goldberg Moses
    - Transcript of interview with Claire Goldberg Moses (Box 10)
  - Camille O'Bryant (Class of 1983) interviewed by Anne Ames, 2013 May 18; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)